Guide to the African American Miscellany, 1757-1983 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
African American Miscellany 1757-1983 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
0.6 Linear Feet 419 Items
Collection of print and manuscript items relating to African and African American history assembled over a number of decades by the staff of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Duke University. Collection contains approximately 400 items documenting the sales, escapes, and emancipations of slaves from colonial times through the Civil War, the civil rights era from 1950-1970, and to a lesser extent, the period in between the 1870s and the 1950s. The documents bring to light details of the lives and deaths of enslaved and free Africans and African Americans in the Southern United States, especially in North Carolina and Virginia, and of economic factors in the trade, sale, and exchange of slaves and other individuals. There are also six albumen studio portrait photographs, mounted on card stock, dating from the second half of the 19th century, along with a copper token from the American Colonization Society, dated 1833.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The items in the African American Miscellany were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library and assembled as an artificial collection from the 1940s to the 1980s.
Collection Overview
Collection of manuscript and print items relating to African and African American history assembled over a number of decades by the staff of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Duke University. Collection contains approximately 400 items dating from 1757-1983 documenting the sales, escapes, and emancipations of slaves from colonial times through the Civil War, the civil rights era from 1950-1970, and to a lesser extent, the period in between the 1870s and the 1950s. Formats include bills of sale and other financial transations; receipts; notes; lists of slaves by names, ages, and sex; wills; insurance policies; emancipation papers; letters; advertisements; clipppings; pamphlets; a few books and serials, and a copybook dating from 1812 with a handwritten poem voicing the support of abolitionism. Among the earliest documents are bills of sale from the 1700s. There are also ships' slave manifests from the "DeKalb" and "Hercules," and one list of slaves and free people in Virginia, 1801-1850. The collection brings to light details of the lives and deaths of enslaved and free Africans and African Americans in the southern United States, primarily in North Carolina, Virginia, and Kentucky, but also in Alabama, Georgia, Louisiana, Maryland, Mississippi, New York, South Carolina, and Tennessee. The collection also contains a series of various items related to the civil rights movement, covering such events as the 1968 Orangeburg Massacre in South Carolina; various readings and speeches from that time; letters from individuals such as Julian Bond and a relative of Medgar Evers; and materials on education in the Southern States, race relations in various states, and on the activities of associations such as the NAACP, with material on Ann Atwater, an activist from Durham, North Carolina. Also includes two letters from NAACP branch offices in 1960, discussing possible support for the lunch counter sit-ins in Greensboro, N.C. There are six albumen studio portrait photographs, mounted on card stock, dating from the second half of the 19th century, along with a copper token from the American Colonization Society, dated 1833.
Collection Arrangement
Collection is arranged into the following series: Slavery, Civil Rights, Other Printed Material, and Artifacts and photographs.The items in each series are arranged in date order, with undated items last.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
African Americans -- History -- 1863-1877
African Americans -- Legal status, laws, etc.--North Carolina
African Americans -- North Carolina -- History -- 18th century
African Americans -- Civil Rights -- North Carolina -- Greensboro
Civil Rights demonstrations -- North Carolina -- Greensboro
African Americans -- North Carolina -- Greensboro
African Americans -- North Carolina -- Greensboro
African Americans -- North Carolina -- History -- 17th century
African Americans -- Social conditions -- 19th century
African American women -- North Carolina -- History -- 19th century
African American women -- United States -- History -- 19th century
African American women -- United States -- Social conditions -- 19th century
Albumen photographs
Antislavery movements -- United States -- History -- 19th century
Atwater, Ann, 1935-.
Bond, Julian
Broadsides
Civil rights movements -- Southern States
Civil rights movements -- United States
Copybooks
Evers, Medgar
Free African Americans -- United States -- History -- 19th century
Free African Americans -- United States -- Social conditions -- 19th century
Freedmen
Fugitive slaves -- United States
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
Slave trade -- Africa
Slave trade -- United States
Slavery -- Alabama -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- Economic aspects -- United States -- History
Slavery -- Georgia -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- Kentucky -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- Louisiana -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- Maryland -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- Mississippi -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- New York -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- North Carolina -- History -- 18th century
Slavery -- North Carolina -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- South Carolina -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- Tennessee -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- Virginia -- History -- 18th century
Slavery -- Virginia -- History -- 19th century
Slavery -- United States -- History -- 19th century
Slaves -- Emancipation -- United States -- History -- 18th century
Slaves -- Emancipation -- United States -- History -- 19th century
Slaves -- Legal status, laws, etc.--United States
Southern States -- History -- 19th century -- African Americans
Tokens.
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- African Americans
Related Material
Broadside Collections
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Slavery Series, 1757-1867 and undated, (1 box, 2 folders)
  Series of documents arranged in chronological order by date from 1757 to 1867 detail the sale of slaves, individuals and groups; prices of slaves; lists of names; runaway slaves; court cases; and many other transactions and events involving enslaved Africans or African Americans. In addition, there are many manuscripts concerning the emancipation or status of free persons of color. Although bills of sale predominate, document formats and genres also include letters, receipts, notes, indentures, deeds, wills or inheritances, ship's manifests, court documents, life insurance policies, information on auctions and markets, bonds, and other financial transactions. There is a copybook dating from 1812 that contains a handwritten poem, The Blood Brother, voicing support for abolitionism. Documents primarily originate from North Carolina, Virginia, and Kentucky, but items from Alabama, Georgia, Louisiana, Maryland, Mississippi, New York, South Carolina, and Tennessee are also present. Details in entries taken directly from documents; in some cases dates and place names were not present or legible. Undated items are found at the end of the series.
  - 1757 Apr.-Nov., Bill of sale, Court of Common Plea, Court at Camden (Box 1)
  - 1757 Mar. 18, Bill of sale for one slave: Beth, 8 year old girl; sold by Lawrence Lancaster to Thomas Cook for £32, 10 shillings
  - 1757 Apr. 17, Bill of sale for one slave boy: Leander, 13 y.o., $1700, to E.H. Simmons
  - 1760 Sept. 1, Bill of sale for one slave girl: 11 y.o., 32 pounds and 10 shillings, from Absalom Lancaster to Thomas Cook
  - 1771 Apr. 17, Bill of sale for one slave, from Aroh Currison to Thomas Cook, N.C.
  - 1779 Feb. 11, Bill of sale for three slaves: Toby, James, and Jacob, from Zachariah Flurry to James Prown, S.C.
  - 1779 Apr. 14, Bill of sale for multiple slaves,, from Dan Heyer, S.C.
  - 1780 Mar. 1, Bill of sale for one slave: Hal, from William Merrit to Rob Long, Chatham County N.C.
  - 1787 Apr. 2, Bill of sale for one slave woman: Catey, 60 pounds and 18 shillings, from Abiyah Holbrook to Samuel Boykin
  - 1794 Apr. 7, Bill of sale for one slave: Glasgow, 48 pounds currency
  - 1794 Oct. 14, Import/Export document for two bales of blankets, imported by Thomas Shaw, New Orleans
  - 1794 Oct. 21, Bond payment slip for 325 pounds to Robert Pasley
  - 1794 Dec. 9, Import document for 50 casks of claret, imported by John Vaughn from Bourdenaux, bound for Port au Prince
  - 1796 Mar. 30, Bill of sale for one slave boy, 70 pounds currency, from William Plummer to Robert Jones of Warren County, Franklin County N.C.
  - 1796 Apr. 5, Emancipation of Edmund, son of Page, a mulatto woman, former property of deceased, Peter Marks, Albemarle County, Va.
  - 1796 Apr. 5, Emancipation of Evelin[e?] Lewis, daughter of Jenny, a mulatto woman, former property of deceased, Peter Marks, Albemarle County, Va.
  - 1798 May 31, John C. Town of Fredrickburg: Neptune York certified born free (about 37 years old, 5 ft. 11 inches); recorded with court September, 1803, Albemarle County, Va.
  - 1799 Aug. 20, Bill of sale for three slaves: one woman, Vilet; one girl, two years, Cheney; one boy, four years, [G?]ack, Cumberland County, N.C.
  - 1800 Apr. 6, Emancipation of two women: Cato (about 65 years old) and Cloe (about 65 years old) freed by John Hudson's will and testament, John Nicholas, Albemarle Co., Va.
  - 1800 Apr. 24, Bond/Account information sheet, owner received a sum of 1000 pounds from W. Fitzpatrick
  - 1801-1850, Register of Negroes and Free People of Color, Rustburg, Va. (oversize)
  - 1801 July 6, Record of emancipation of female, Frankey, by John Nicholas, Albemarle Co., Va.
  - 1802 Feb. 2, Bill of sale for two slaves: Mary and her daughter Eliza, to Henry Dana Ward, S.C., Northern Circuit
  - 1805 Mar. 5, Bill of sale for one slave boy, $350, to James Parrant
  - 1805 June 24, Bill of sale for two slave boys, $520
  - 1805 Oct 11, Two bills of sale transactions on one leaf, for Harriet, aged 20, and her daughter Elizabeth, aged 6 months, $280; and Delilah, $213, to George Legg., Baltimore, Md.
  - 1806 Nov. 20, A note proclaiming freedom, John Walker: Nancy Gardiner, a mulatto girl, age 20, born free to a free mother, Albamarle Co., Ala.
  - 1807 Feb. 17, Account balancing slip of paper
  - 1808 Dec. 27, Decree of gift of five slaves: Phill, woman, Luckey, young woman, Nanny, young woman, Allen, small boy, and Harry, small boy, from Col. John Hamilton of Norfolk, Va. to Mrs. Patey Brickall and her three children
  - 1809 Apr., Bill of sale for one slave woman, $400, Tenn.
  - 1809 May 6, Bill of sale for one slave boy: Abraham, 90 pounds, from Daniel Jackson Manea to John Kelly, Granville County, N.C.
  - 1810 June 4, Bill of sale for one slave girl, $287, from David Hensler and William Maxwell of Rockingham District N.C. to Hardy Clemmond of Pendleton District, S.C.
  - 1810 Nov. 1, Bill of sale for one slave woman: Serena, and her child, $440, from M. Stokes to Samuel Guy
  - 1811 Mar. 1, Bill of sale for one slave girl, $350, to Samuel Grey
  - 1811-1814, certifications of the freedom of seven men: Thomas Pritchard, Scipio Melden, William Anthony, James De Hart, Henry Tafe, Joshua Bornish, John Roberts, Court of Common Plea, 5th Ward, New York, NY, (7 documents)
  - 1811 May 2, Slip of paper: "Thomas Thomson"
  - 1812 Jan. 23, Bill of sale for one slave man: Dave, 27 y.o., $400, to William Sutton
  - 1812 Nov. 18, Bill of sale for one slave: Hannah, from William Brumfield to Richard Jones
  - 1812 Dec. 9, Bill of sale for tract of land and two slaves: Harriet, girl, and Tanney, woman, from Mr. Maybanch, Liberty County, Ga.
  - 1812-1817, copybook belonging to Mary Hamlins of Salem, Ohio; includes practice scripts, arithmetic, and a poem, The Blood Brother, in support of abolition, (17 pages)
  - 1813 Aug. 6, Bill of sale for one slave boy: Henry, 14 y.o., $300, from William Bennett to Richard Jones, Pittsylvania County, Va.
  - 1813 Dec. 9, Bill of sale for one slave woman: Sue, $300, to Mr. Ballins
  - 1815 Sept. 27, Empancipation of slave woman and daughter: Sue and Margaret, from Elizabeth Graham, Georgetown District, S.C.; also gives the former slaves $50 from her estate
  - 1817 May 12, Bill of sale for two slaves: woman Amy, 27 y.o. and her child Sidney, 8 m.o., $400, from Joseph and Margaret Lawrence to Samuel Guy
  - 1818 Feb. 18, Bill of sale for one slave girl: Esther, 20 y.o., $1500, from William Astin of Va. to Samuel Grey
  - 1818 Nov. 8, Bill of sale for one slave: Daniel, from Millie Allen to Robert Park
  - 1821 Oct. 4, List of assets, including slaves, of Adam Corraths
  - 1822 Jan. 14, Paper certifying that the children of Moses and Marian, named Susan, Israel and Rachel, were free
  - 1822 June 1, Bill of sale for one slave woman: Bell, 24 y.o., $550, from Kenneth Clarke to John Bethan, Moore County, Md.
  - 1822 Oct. 17, Bill of sale for one slave boy: Bedford, $309, from Mark Weatherly to Martin Weatherly, N.C.
  - 1823 Apr. 12, Bill of sale for slaves, $597.92, from John Cawley, S.C.
  - 1823 Apr. 29, Bill of sale for one slave woman: Jenny, $300, from Edmund Hoskins to Joseph Blount, N.C.
  - 1824 Mar. 31, Bill of sale for four slaves: Milly, 2 y.o., Ann, 5 y.o., Jack, 2 y.o., and Mary, 8 m.o., $777, from James and Josiah Huie to Samuel Guy
  - 1824 Oct. 23, Bill of sale for one slave, $251, to Sam Woods
  - 1824 Nov., Bill of sale for one slave man: Dave, 35 y.o., $325, to Samuel Guy
  - 1824 Nov. 15, Bill of sale for one slave girl: Beck, 14 y.o., $300, to Samuel Guy
  - 1825 June 14, Letter discussing the author's a visit from the author's brother, Richard, and the freeing slaves to Martha Moore of N.C.
  - 1827 June 1, Trust deed between William Scott, Richard Wallace, and John Pilson in which Scott gives Wallace slaves as collateral: Phyllis, woman, her child Robert Wilson, and two slave men, Jesse and Ben
  - 1827 Dec. 22, Bill of sale for one slave: Ben, 9 y.o., $200
  - 1827 Dec. 22, Bill of sale for three slaves: Jimmy, Milton, and Carter, from Peter Winn to William Ryan of Guilford County, N.C.
  - 1828 Feb. 9, Bill of sale for one slave girl: 19 y.o., from Alexander Hogan to Samuel Guy
  - 1828 July, Bill of sale for two slave boys: Richard and Benjamin, $1200
  - 1828 Sept. 27, Bill of sale for one slave woman, $550, from J.K. Shelton to Richard Jones, Pittslyvania County
  - 1829 Jan. 16, Emancipation note of slave John Brown, from Isaac Bett, Md.
  - 1829 Apr. 25, Document certifying the freedom of Elias, Frederick County, Md.
  - 1829 May 14, Bill of sale for one slave boy: Adam, $200, from John Mae Bullers of Johnston County to Gilbert Multon, Richmond County, N.C.
  - 1829 July 16 - 1830 Jan. 4, Notes to the Caroline County Jailer asking him to take slaves into custody, slaves named: Adam, Randal, Walker, Jim, and Eldrid, (6 documents)
  - 1829 Aug. 21, Bill of sale for four slaves: Milly, Jim, 7 y.o., Eliza, 4 y.o., and Isaac, 18 m.o., to Gilbert Mae Millan, Richmond County, Fayetteville, N.C.
  - 1830 Jan. 18, Notice announcing a slave sale to be held at Pittsylvania Courthouse [Va.?]
  - 1830 Apr. 16, Document certifying the freedom of Matthew Scroggins, 28 y.o., 5 ft. 5 in., Frederick County, Md.
  - 1830 Sept. 2, Document certifying the freedom of Solomon, Frederick County, Md.
  - 1831 Feb. 28, Paper from Thomas Berry detailing two bills of sale proclaiming that "William Williams, a colored man," wanted to purchase his wife and child from Berry
  - 1831 Apr. 19, Bill of sale for one slave: Dianah, $250, from Benjamin Grandstaff to Mr. Rice, Shenandoah County, Va.
  - 1832 Jan. 4, Bill of sale for one slave: Henry, 18 y.o., $450, from Morgan Davis to James Bistand of Adam County, Miss.
  - 1832 May 7, Document certifying the freedom of Betsy, Frederick County, Md.
  - 1832 Sept. 24, Court proceedings from Nelson County [Va.? Ky.?]
  - 1832 Dec. 8, Bond of indemnity to the Captain of the barque "Hercules," a ship that took S.C. and Ga. "colored persons" from Savannah to Liberia.
  - 1835 June 29, Ship manifest for the schooner "Dekalb" of "Negroes, Mulattoes, and Persons of Color," District of Baltimore, Port of Baltimore
  - 1835 Sept. 1, Response to John Hunt about his notice of selling 60 slaves, New Orleans
  - 1836 Nov. 1, Bill of sale for two slaves: James Ross's document notarized by Maria Cohen; free black woman sells Eve's children; sale of two slaves for $500 to Levi S. D'tyon - slaves: Nancy, age 8, and John, age 6
  - 1838 Apr. 23, Statement of the slaves belonging to heirs of John L. Ward, Richard Ward to Martha A. Power, an heir
  - 1838, Dec. 18, Bill of sale for two slave women, $1200, from Cole to Farmer, Halifax County [N.C.? Va.?]
  - 1839 June 13, Bill of sale for one slave man: Philip, $400, S.C.
  - 1840 Jan. 10, Note for rental of slave man for one year from S. and N. Buck: Bill, including furnishing with winter clothing, shoes, stockings and blanket, $97.50, to Joseph Snapp, Front Royal area, Va.
  - 1840 Feb. 8, Bill of sale for one slave boy: Ralph, 16 y.o., $650, to Nancy Robards, N.C.
  - 1840 Nov. 2, Bill of sale for one slave: Sheriff's Bill of Sale - sale of Warren, negro boy, about seven years of age for $202; buyer: Mrs. Hannah L., [B], South Carolina
  - 1841 Nov. 1, Bill of sale for one mulatto man: Lewis, $800, from public auction to Franklin Mores, Sheriff's Office, Sumter District, S.C.
  - 1843 July 7, Bill of sale for one slave man: Jim, 26 y.o., $500, to William Mitchell, Ga.
  - 1844, Return of property notice for six slaves: Mariah, Hester, Adam, Sarah, Sigga, and Jane, to Paul H. Allen
  - 1844 Oct., Bill of sale for one slave man: Jacob, $187.50, to Richard Jones
  - 1844 Dec. 27, Note for rental of a slave woman from James R. Richards (executor? of the will of William Hopewells) for one year: Henrietta, including furnishing with winter clothing, shoes, and blanket, $27.50, to [J. & I] Trout, Front Royal area, Va.
  - 1845 Mar. 12, Bill of sale for one slave and blacksmith tools: Ben, blacksmith, from John Ing to Bryant Young
  - 1846 Dec. 1, Bill of sale for one slave girl: Caroline, 22 y.o., $401, from public auction to Richard R. Winfrey, Hall County, Ga.
  - 1847 Dec. 8, Bill of sale for one slave woman: Matilda, and her two children, $550, from Peter Griggs
  - 1848 Feb. 29-Oct. 29, Payments, Mr. C. Pettejohn
  - 1843-1849, Paper detailing four bills of sale
  - 1849, Bill of sale for one slave boy: George, 11 y.o., $450, to Emmanuel George
  - 1849 Jan. 15, Affidavit certifying the freedom of a mulatto woman, 42 y.o., saying the woman was born free, written by M. Hugh Owens, Frederick County, Md.
  - 1849 May 11, Bill of sale for one slave woman and her two children, $812, to William B. Enecks, Barnwell District, S.C.
  - 1849 July 5, Check for one slave: Davy, $485, written by C.H. Simmons
  - 1849 Oct. 3, Bill of sale for one slave woman, $600, from Richard Jones to Janus Pointer, Pittsylvania County, Va.
  - 1849 Dec. 21, Bill of sale for one slave: Susan, $575, from E. Bellin to E.H. Simmons
  - 1849 Dec. 22, Bill of sale for four slaves: George, Lucy, Louisa, and Piemus, $1600, from Freeman Hoyt to E.H. Simmons, Charleston, S.C.
  - 1850 Mar. 4, Documents pertaining to the sale of one slave: Jenny, $618, from James M. Fitts to Henry E. Solomons, Beaufort District, Charleston, S.C., (2 documents)
  - 1850 Apr. 1, Documents pertaining to the Will of Martin Weatherly: heirs deciding his estate, mentions slaves, Francis, Viney and her son Aaron, (2 documents)
  - 1850 Sept. 28, Bill of sale for one slave boy: Aron, 10 y.o., $457.50, from Erwin Hurmer to Jacob Coble
  - 1850 Oct. 3, Bill of sale for one slave girl: Sally, 11 y.o., $450, from Hall and Johnson to Richard Jones
  - 1851 Mar. 14, Auction notes and prizes, New Orleans
  - 1851 July 25, Arrest warrant for slave Isaac for actions on board steamboat Mary Washington, including assaults and threats made against Warren Moudowney, Corporation of Fredericksburg
  - 1852 Aug. 14, Bill of sale for one slave woman and her two children: Sally: 24 y.o., Lear, 2 y. and 10 m.o., and Deanah, 9 m.o., $1005, to Paul D. Felder, Orangeburgh District, S.C.
  - 1853 June 29, transfer of slaves Viney and her daughter of 18 mos., Adelia, from Hezakiah and Sarah Thompson to their daughter, Adelaide Kemp, St. Helen's Parish, La.
  - 1853 Aug. 6, Bill of sale for one slave girl: Mariah, 14 y.o., $200, from Emanuel Geiger to Alexander Forsyth, selling because of "falling fits"
  - 1853 Dec. 27, Note for rental of slave woman for one year from [Schew's] & McKay: Maria, including furnishing with winter clothing, shoes, stockings, bonnet, and blanket, $36, to [name excised], Front Royal area, Va.
  - 1855 Jan. 1, Details of will of Thomas John, deceased on 1849 May 3, Warren County, Ky. Owned slaves: George, Richard, Catherine, Louisa, and Martha, states that they should be freed 15 yr. after his death. Includes a purchase agreement for Martha, $350, for sale to Matthew Smith
  - 1855 Dec. 13, Bills of sale from the executor's sale of the estate of Charles E. Clark: Clarissa and her two children, Eliza and unamed infant; Matilda and her child, Fanny, (2 documents)
  - 1856 Feb. 15, Bill of sale for one slave girl: Jenny, 12 y.o., $700, to Alfred Carson
  - 1856 Aug. 2, Bill of sale for two slaves: Emilie, 18 y.o., and Eve, 3 y.o., $1000, from Lucien Monteguet to Nathaniel Williamson, New Orleans
  - 1857 Jan. 25, Bill of sale for three slaves: Kitty, woman, 22 y.o., Kirt, boy, 3 y.o., and Burt, boy, 10 m.o., $1600, from Mahala F. Bowie to Hugh McDonald, Miss.
  - 1857 Feb. 2, Bill of sale for one slave woman: Sukey, 45 y.o., $400, from Thomas Bradshaw, Alamance County, N.C.
  - 1857 Feb. 2. Bill of sale for one slave boy: Mel, $730, from Sheriff's Office to G.M. Tusen, Beaufort District, S.C.
  - 1857 Feb. 12, Notes on slaves received from A. Bland's will by his two heirs, George and Albert: Young Peter, Butter, Jo, Rose, Charlotte, Young Isaac, Irvin, Harriet, Amy, Pink Jerry, Mary, Old Peter, Augusta, Isaac, Sneky, Victoria, Anderson, Charles, Pliant, Bill, Henry, Betsy, Sabra, Perry, Prince, Emily, Melissa, Gracy, Dick, Eliza, Edmond, Claire, and Jim, (2 documents)
  - 1857 Apr. 30, Bill of sale for one slave boy, Henry, 9 years, $400, from Jacob Semly to G. Davidson
  - 1857 Aug. 8, Bill of sale for one slave boy, Grandison, from M.C. Manning
  - 1857 Dec. 26, Indenture to hire man, Peter, for year 1858, from Samuel Williams to J. White
  - 1857 Dec. 28, Note for rental of slave woman for one year from Ann H. Millar: Lucinda, including furnishing with shirts, dresses, petticoats, stockings, aprons, shoes, and blanket, $50, to Isaac Trout, Front Royal area, Va.